♪ Got those blue skies
up above ♪
Meredith:
My mother always used to say
that you could tell the
difference between an intern
and a second-year resident
by their sutures.
Wait, ladybug, you forgot
your lunch again.
Made your favorite.
♪ Mm, mm
♪ Oh, oh, oh
My favorite.
Go back inside, Grammy.
Dad's getting your breakfast.
Bye, baby.
Love you.
♪ Ain't got no reason
to complain ♪
♪ No, no, no
One of the more common
mistakes an intern makes
is tying their sutures
too tightly,
which causes tension.
♪ ...at all that's going down
Wow.
Right? It's my first.
Car?
Place.
I installed a Wi-Fi hotspot
and a camper stove. Ah.
And, no,
you can't borrow it.
[ Watch beeps ]
The more tension, the longer
it takes the wound to heal.
It decreases blood flow,
increases scar formation,
and even necroses the skin.
What are you doing?
I worked till 4:00 a.m.
Thought I'd put on
fresh underwear.
Please do not tell me
that you are living here.
I'm not.
It's just a safe space
to put my stuff
till I find a permanent place.
Oh, my God.
Please don't say anything
to my mom.
I don't even
talk to your mom!
Ah, this whole sister hate thing
may work in my favor.
Okay, just come stay
at Meredith's for a few days.
If you're gonna survive
internship here,
you're gonna need a night
or two of good sleep. Nope.
You at least need
to do laundry.
You're offering
to wash my underwear?
We agreed.
No special favors.
So even though they may have
technically closed the wound...
Lucas: Hey.
...they may have opened
the door to even more problems.
♪ Yeah, yeah
We're late.
♪ Oh, it's a good, good day
Whoa, whoa!
Slow down!
My God.
We almost just died.
Have you seen these e-mails
about Nick Marsh's plans for
the residency program?
It's weird.
The Residency Director
is e-mailing
about the residents.
He wants to push pre-rounds
by an hour,
set up a mixer
with the nursing staff,
and wants to bring in
a yoga instructor.
Oh! When?
When will they work?
I mean, he's doing exactly
what I thought he would,
but I just thought
he would, I don't know,
stop by my office or
send me an e-mail or call me.
Sounds like this is not entirely
about the way he does his job.
The job
that you offered him.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
[ All chuckle ]
So, I suppose I will
see you ladies tonight.
Did you forget?
Zola's presentation
for the Pacific
Northwest Scholars.
Her paper is a finalist for
their merit program.
What's the paper about?
Her hero.
Dr. Ellis Grey.
Twist.
I don't care.
I'll show up for anything
that celebrates Zola.
I'll see you tonight.
See you.
Woman: [ Over intercom ]
Nurse Krueger to the O.R.
Hello. Listen up.
Dr. Schmitt
is your chief resident.
[ Quietly ]
He's our only senior resident.
He's gonna be handing out
your assignments
while I'm doing
a kidney transplant.
Who can name
the top three causes
of end-stage
renal disease?
Hypertension, diabetes, glomerulonephritis.
He didn't raise his hand.
Yeah, I don't care
about any of that.
Am I correct?
Yeah, you are.
Do I get to scrub in?
No, uh, you cannot.
Okay.
Have fun, Schmitt.
♪
I haven't slept
in two days.
I am answering pages
from six different services,
and I had a cupcake for
breakfast, so no one complain.
Adams, you're with Dr. Pierce.
Kwan's with Ndugu.
Yasuda,
report to Owen Hunt.
And, uh, Millin and Griffith,
surgical consult in the pit.
Uh, two of us
for one consult?
Two interns
make a whole doctor.
Now, don't embarrass me
or kill anyone
or drop anything
inside a patient.
♪
This is the moment you go.
Come on.
♪
Dr. Kwan.
Yeah.
Tell me what you see.
[ Exhales sharply ]
Pericardial effusion?
That's right,
which is compressing
this patient's heart.
What would be
your recommendation?
Hi! Remember Mr. Veras?
He's back,
and his trach is infected.
Can you take a look?
Also, a new patient in 523
needs an echo
and admissions orders
for observation.
Are you talking to me
or--
Always assume I'm not.
I have a VATS lobectomy
in an hour.
I pushed that
to this afternoon.
Maggie, I already rescheduled
that patient twice.
I double-checked
his labs.
A few hours will not
change his status.
Okay, uh, yeah,
I will get it all done.
Thank you.
I will check in with you
after
my valve replacement.
We're doing a valve replacement?
What type of valve?
TAVR.
But you are on scut.
No special favors, right?
Uh--
Uh...
All I did was
put in a chest tube.
Was there an attending
in the room?
It's the E.R., Teddy.
There's about three attendings
in this area at all times.
Was one specifically
watching you?
One specifically has been
barking at me 24/7,
so, yeah, I assumed
she was still here.
Do you need something?
Mika Yasuda,
reporting for
Dr. Hunt's service.
I'm his intern today.
[ Laughs ]
You know, you might
want to find a new service.
Yeah, Dr. Hunt used to be
chief of trauma,
and then he lost his mind,
so now I'm chief of trauma.
Yeah, also, she's my lovely wife
and mother of my children.
Her favorite color
is blue.
Did she really need
to know that?
Yes.
To humanize you!
According to the Washington
Medical Commission,
if he attempts to do anything
on his own,
he will be reported
and lose his medical license.
Understood?
Oh, so I'm supposed to...
Call an additional attending
for the following--
intubations,
chest tubes,
surgical consults,
I&Ds, NG tubes,
lap repairs, washouts...
[ Man vomiting ]
Pretty sure
this isn't surgical.
Well, don't
give up hope yet.
So, when did the, uh--
the vomiting start?
I can't remember.
Any alcohol last night?
Drugs?
We shared a few drinks
while playing "Barn Finders"
at a friend's apartment. Oh.
It's a video game.
You play?
Sometimes.
Not at all.
Yeah, we got back
at like 3:00 a.m.,
and, uh, we split
some leftover fried rice
I had in my fridge.
It's from that place
across the street
from the student union.
We are never ordering
from there again.
[ Vomiting ]
Any blood
in your vomit?
I-I don't know. Here.
Okay, well, we'll get you both
started on some IV fluids,
and then we'll give you
another run--
[ Gasping ]
Okay, just-- Just stay calm.
Okay? Take a deep breath
for me if you can.
Uh, Dr. Griffith,
we need some oxygen
here, please.
On it.
Okay.
What's happening to him?!
[ Grunting ]
Uh, hold on.
Hold on.
[ Groaning ]
What the hell is this?
I don't know.
Well, find
somebody who does!
[ Groaning ]
Okay. [ Grunts ]
Hi!
Hi, Pru! Luna, say hi!
Okay, healthy snacks, check.
Uh, sanitizer, check.
This is my kind of mom group.
No endless brunches,
no power walking in full makeup
and earrings
and tight leggings.
Alright, waters,
uh, baby wipes, yes,
and, uh, sunscreen.
You are organized.
Not my first rodeo.
Thank you so much for calling.
All I do is work
and watch Link bring home
half the women in Seattle,
which, you know, I'm not one
to judge a choice, but it--
Uh-huh. Okay.
Look, if we hurry,
the girls can go down the slide
while it's still in the shade.
Oh. Uh, are we late?
Yes. Let's power-walk.
[ Sighing ] Okay.
[ Indistinct announcement
over intercom ]
Did you page both of us?
Uh, I paged Chief Grey.
I paged Dr. Webber.
Did you happen to talk to
each other before doing that?
Uh, never mind. Never mind.
Uh, what do you got?
Um, 19-year-old male
with abdominal pain,
vomiting, and chills.
He recently was
experiencing chest pain,
shortness of breath, and a rash
on his abdomen and chest.
Meredith: Okay.
What about him?
College roommate.
They ate the same thing
four hours before
both presenting with
food poisoning symptoms,
but he hasn't developed a rash
or shortness of breath.
It's on his legs
and his arms, also.
Let's get blood cultures,
get a chest X-ray.
Put him on high-flow oxygen.
Admit him to the ICU.
Call internal medicine
and page us when you're done.
One of us.
♪
Excuse me. Hi.
Do I need
all that stuff, too?
So, your intake form says that
you're experiencing
abdominal discomfort,
Mr. Peters?
Harold, please.
But I may know what
the discomfort is from--
There you are!
This hospital's a maze.
Sharon, I told you
to wait in the car.
And I told you I thought
that was a stupid idea.
I still can't find my phone.
What if the kids call
and need something?
You won't be able to help
if you're on an operating table.
What's wrong with him?
I'm fine.
Probably an ulcer
or something.
He says that
every time we're supposed
to go to my mother's.
Your abdomen is distended,
so I'm gonna have
to do an ultrasound
to figure out
how to proceed, okay?
I have three minutes.
And I'm not sure
I'm gonna survive them.
Do I need to remind you
why I'm here, Dr. Hunt?
Well, it's been about 10 minutes
since the last time,
so, sure,
knock yourself out.
Are you all doctors?
Teddy, this is
just an ultrasound.
So then it should go quick.
Hi, I'm Dr. Altman.
Yes, we are all doctors.
And you're all necessary?
No. You know what? Why don't
you just do this yourself?
Well, if I were to do
everything myself,
then no one would learn.
Would they?
We're a teaching hospital.
We should have gone
to Seattle Pres.
Levi: Oh, geez.
I'll be right back.
Mika: Dr. Schmitt.
I was supposed
to remove the drains
from Dr. Ndugu's patient
an hour ago.
I have to go round
on Webber's post-ops,
and the nurses keep
texting me angry emojis.
I can't work for Dr. Hunt
because it means
you're also working
for Dr. Altman,
which means you're working
for velociraptors.
They're vicious,
can snap in an instant,
but there is
a mind-game component
going on between those two
that is so deep,
it might destroy
all of civilization.
Short, succinct,
clear sentences.
What?
I don't have time to pee,
and you just said
so many words.
Can I be on your service
instead of Dr. Hunt's?
No.
Now get back in there
and do your job.
[ Indistinct announcement
over intercom ]
Thank you.
Hey. I just asked Winston
if he could help on an anterior
approach for a spinal fusion,
and he said
to check with you?
He's monitoring
a few patients for me,
and I may need an assist
on a TAVR.
Well, I can assist
on the TAVR.
Out.
Is everything okay
with Winston?
He seemed a little--
Was he doing his scissors talk?
I don't know
what you mean.
When Winston gets irritated,
he talks like scissors--
Like, every word,
it sounds like snip, snip, snip.
He wants to yell,
but he holds back,
so he just cuts the air
with his words.
I thought
he was mad at me.
No, he's mad at me.
[ Sighs ]
I pushed his surgery
because I'm a perfectionist
and I want perfection
for my patients.
And there's no such thing
as perfection in interns,
and there are still
no senior residents,
so I ask perfect Winston.
Yeah, well, I still need someone
to help on my spinal fusion,
so you need to work
on all that.
[ Sighs ]
We do have
one senior resident.
Dr. Schmitt.
Page him.
And don't eavesdrop on
my conversations.
[ Monitors beeping rapidly ]
What happened?
He became completely unresponsive,
and his pressure tanked.
The rash is now everywhere.
Let's start him on pressors.
Push sux, etomidate.
Get me an intubation tray.
[ Monitors continue
beeping rapidly ]
Two of you, come around here.
Stand behind me.
Watch exactly what I'm doing.
You want to make sure
you have full visualization
of the vocal cords.
♪
Griffith, come around
and listen for breath sounds.
♪
Bilateral breath sounds.
Okay, great job.
Thank you.
♪
Uh, Chief Grey?!
♪ Well, your touch
holds me captive ♪
Hey, I need you
to come back to work now.
I make more money here.
You do not.
Uh, as a resident, I made
around 55K a year, before taxes,
when I regularly worked
80-hour weeks,
and weekends
and holidays.
The math sucks, Levi.
Not to mention
I didn't love the stress
that came with it.
If I make a mistake here,
nobody dies.
Taryn,
you are a surgeon.
I was a surgeon.
Now I'm a bartender
and you're on
the vagina squad.
Was!
I was on the vagina squad.
Now I am chief resident,
general surgery.
Only because
I'm not coming back.
Disagree.
So come back
and prove me wrong.
No.
Grey wants you back.
Did she say that?
[ Chuckles ]
Meredith is straight,
and I have enough
self-esteem now to know
to only fall for women
who might love me back.
So, thanks,
but no thanks.
Wow.
Bartending really is
good for you, huh?
Right?
[ Sighs ]
[ Fake sobbing ]
Please come back anyway.
No!
Oh!
[ Cellphone chimes ]
Ugh!
I'm coming, Dr. Pierce.
Bye.
♪
Meredith: Initially presented
like textbook food poisoning,
and then evolved into
septic shock within hours.
Do we have the source
of infection?
Uh, no. Not yet.
His chest X-ray shows
bilateral pleural effusions,
and he's exhibiting
signs of DIC.
The rash is non-blanching.
It could be petechiae.
I initially thought it was
Steven Johnson Syndrome,
but the rash
doesn't peel with pressure.
Any case reports
of Bacillus cereus
and sepsis after eating rice?
It's not Bacillus cereus.
It's not food poisoning
at all.
Have any of you ever seen a
patient bleed from every orifice
after eating
bad leftover rice?
Well, then solve it.
What?
You and Millin
and the rest of the interns,
hit the research
and figure it out.
Before it's too late.
♪
Hello, Altman.
Well, I'm glad you and Hunt
decided to come back.
I imagine it's hard
with everything he has
to go through right now.
Let me guess. Owen thinks that
I'm drinking too much,
so he asked you
to intervene.
Thanks. I'm good.
I was just asking
how you were doing.
Well, I have spent the last
six months on my feet
working locum tenens
in L.A.
while Owen developed
an artistic penchant
for building sand castles,
which was fun for the kids,
but, honestly, the sand castles
were pretty basic.
And since his legal team
bankrupted us,
Owen and I now have lengthy
arguments about important topics
like whether to buy name-brand
or store-brand shampoo.
Every time I look at his face,
I am filled with such annoyance
that I have to go outside
and pretend to garden
when, really, my kids are
just seeing me rip up plants.
The worst part
of all of it is--
is that I still
don't want to leave him
because he's the father
of my kids,
and somewhere really deep down
inside, I still love him.
And wine helps me
remember that,
so I drink three glasses
a night.
But never at work.
And the kids are in bed
by 8:00,
and I don't get
behind the wheel.
I mean, the riskiest thing
that I may do
is watch too many
puppy videos at night.
Is that a problem
for you, sir?
Always good
to see you, Altman.
Hey! Adams.
Dr. Shepherd.
I wanted
to run something by you.
About a patient.
I'll catch up.
♪
I found you
some apartments to see.
Mom always said
you were the best liar.
That was bad lying.
Wait, is that a loft?
Eh, kinda.
I think there's some creative
license with the advertising,
but it's near Meredith's.
Uh, great,
send it to me.
You can visit, see the kids,
eat for free.
You won't see me cook,
but Meredith's pretty good,
and Maggie makes dinner
on Sundays.
Hey, can you not
walk so close?
What's wrong with you?
You're hovering.
I'm helping.
The more people see us together,
the easier it's gonna be
for them to figure out
we're related.
I've already been designated
the screw-up.
Please don't make it worse. Bye.
You know, it could be
toxic shock syndrome.
That would explain
the rash.
But there's no liver
or renal dysfunction.
Have you considered
erythema multiforme?
No one asked you.
I asked him.
What?
Chief Grey told us to.
I will ask everyone
if it prevents my name
going on a death certificate.
So, who's dying?
How can we help?
It's a 19-year-old male,
ate leftover fried rice,
vomited for six hours,
a generalized, purple,
star-shaped rash
all over his body, and is now
in full-blown septic shock.
Ah, he looks
pretty dead already.
That's from bad rice?
I've never seen
so much vomit,
and my parents did
a lot of hallucinogens.
And it was like a--
like a rainbow of vomit.
Like red-brown,
yellow-green, bilious.
I'm done.
DRESS syndrome?
No. He doesn't take
any meds,
and his eosinophil count
is normal.
- Kawasaki disease?
- No.
[ Cellphone vibrates, chimes ]
[ Sighs ]
Ugh. I have to go
find an attending
to supervise my attending
so they can supervise
me learning nothing.
Simone: Have fun.
Rickettsial disease?
No.
It's not even your case.
Well, that should tell you
how wrong you are.
Harold, so, your ultrasound
didn't show any abnormalities,
so we're gonna do a CT scan
to get a better look, okay?
[ Quietly ] Is it possible
to get some privacy?
You and I? Without--
Oh, um, Dr. Yasuda,
can you take Mrs. Peters
to grab a coffee?
Yeah. Mrs. Peters,
if you would just follow me--
Oh! It's here.
I used the app to locate
my phone. It's in here.
Let me call it.
Sharon, please--
Ah, Harold,
give me two seconds,
and you can be alone
all you want.
I really need you to leave.
[ Cellphone vibrating ]
Sharon!
Shh-shh-shh-shh.
[ Cellphone vibrating ]
Oh, for God's sake,
are you sitting on it?
It sounds like it's coming
directly from yo--
Mm.
Harold,
did you stick my phone
up your ass?
Please say no.
You're always
on the damn thing!
Oh, my God.
We don't even know
what your face
looks like anymore
'cause you're glued
to social media!
Unbelievable.
Ow!
Oh, my God!
Page Dr. Altman
so I can retrieve
the [clears throat]
phone.
Hang it up!
Yeah. Oh, oh, God.
Bailey: So, are things at least
improving at Grey-Sloan?
How are you doing it?
Doing what?
Not breaking things
and sobbing uncontrollably
and screaming in public
every time
you look at Pru's face
and think about the world
that she's growing up in?
I try to remember
she's already lost one parent,
and if I did something
to get myself arrested,
no one would be there
to read her
"The Pout-Pout Fish" at bedtime.
I mean, Ben,
he just reads the words.
I do it with the rhythm.
[ Humming rhythmically ]
Carina and I
did extend our clinic hours
to accommodate the patients
from out of state.
Oh. Are you having to pick up
more hours in surgery,
or has that calmed down
now that the interns are back?
No!
What?
I thought you wanted
to be my mom friend.
[ Chuckling ]
I'm just making conversation.
You are using me for
information about the hospital.
You want me to be
your Deep Throat!
I prefer Delta Source...
[ Scoffs ]
...an Imperial
intelligence source
during the early years
of the New Republic.
Well, you gonna talk
or not?
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Alright, Harold,
let me know
if you feel
any discomfort, okay?
Physical or emotional?
Uh, we're gonna be fast.
Okay, Yasuda,
I need you to press hard
on the lower left
quadrant, okay?
Don't forget gloves.
I'm beginning to understand
why you did this, Harold.
What?
Okay, ready here.
Okay, here we go.
Now, Harold,
I'm gonna need you
to bear down.
No one should ever say that
to another human being.
And push.
[ Straining ]
Alright, try forceps
or a balloon catheter.
Push harder, Harold.
[ Grunting ]
Owen, if you can't grasp it,
he's gonna have to go
to the operating room.
[ Phone clangs ]
[ Sighs ] You wanna take that
to his wife?
Hmm?
♪
I'm the guy who killed
his college roommate.
They're gonna make
podcasts about me.
He is not dead.
And I believe
we can save him
once we know exactly
how to treat him.
Can you tell me
anything you know about him?
Um, he's from Massachusetts.
Parents are divorced,
and I don't ask about it
'cause my parents are divorced
and I don't like
talking about it.
Uh, he's a history major,
loves sports documentaries,
hates coffee, I mean--
Anything you know
about his health.
Oh. Um...
He had syphilis once.
[ Siren wails in distance ]
[ Indistinct announcement
over intercom ]
Hello.
Hey.
Hi.
How was the, uh,
kidney transplant?
Uh, well,
it's making urine already,
so, you know, on par. Good.
Yeah.
Good.
And you're liking
the, um, new position?
I saw all the changes
that you made.
Yeah. Uh,
is there an issue?
Not at all.
Okay, good.
Where are you staying?
You know,
same place on Union.
Oh.
I like that place.
Yeah, you're acting
a little weird.
Excuse me. Chief Grey?
Yes.
Um, it's Chase.
Oh. Okay. Sorry.
Good luck. Sorry.
Link: His foot's cold,
and I can't get a Doppler signal
anywhere below the knee.
We don't make a move,
this leg could
turn gangrenous.
Any family around?
His mother is on a plane
as we speak.
Well, if she wants
to see her son alive,
that leg's gotta go.
You have to amputate?
You do.
I'm sorry, what?
Cutting something off
is way easier
than reattaching it.
Get him prepped
and upstairs.
♪
Maggie: Advance the guide wire
carefully to the aortic annulus.
Levi:
It's very angulated here.
I don't want
to injure anything.
It's okay. Just go slowly.
[ Doors slide open ]
There. Good.
Winston: Schmitt,
why aren't you in O.R. 4?
Because I am trying really hard
not to injure
this man's vasculature
in thi O.R.
You prepped and studied
for my VATS lobectomy.
And if I remember correctly,
you begged to be my assist.
If you were supposed
to be his assist,
then why are you
in here being mine?
The schedule
changed so much.
And you are
chief of cardio.
And I play Dungeons & Dragons,
so I follow hierarchy.
And for the record,
I'm very tired.
Please don't say that
with your hands in my patient.
I thought
I was helping you.
By taking my assist
to be yours?
Winston--
Alright, you know what?
I'll reschedule
the lobectomy again.
Hi.
Oh, uh, Marsh. Yeah.
What exactly is
"mini Grand Rounds,"
and why was I invited?
Uh, we did them
in Minnesota.
Interns take turns presenting
on cases to their class.
It helps their skills for rounds
and future lecture capabilities.
So it's good.
Well, what am I
supposed to do?
Well, I thought
you could be there
to help me
provide feedback.
Look,
is this gonna be a thing?
Someone questions me every time
I make a change to the program?
Because I kinda thought
that's why I was hired here.
Look, um, six months ago,
I was trying everything I could
to save this place.
My wife wasn't doing well.
I blamed you for Meredith
going to Minnesota.
I wasn't my best self.
I've already apologized
to Meredith about it.
And, um, well,
you deserve the same.
I'm sorry.
I appreciate that,
Dr. Webber, I do, but...
it does kinda feel like
there's more here.
Oh, no. N--
[ Sighs ]
Well, okay, yes.
Um,
it's none of my business,
and I'm not exactly sure what
happened between the two of you,
but, um, she's worth
taking a job for.
If that's why you did it.
And I'd be honored
to join you for feedback.
Okay.
Oh, and, uh, Marsh, uh,
program's yours now.
[ "Are You Ready" by Kenny Sharp
playing ]
♪ Ah, ah
♪
♪ From my head to my toes,
from my heart to my soul ♪
♪ Feel my pulse, yeah,
it's racing electric ♪
I thought you were getting
to scrub in with Dr. Ndugu.
[ Sighs ]
His wife rescheduled it.
♪ Keep my spirit alive
He's married to Dr. Pierce,
and there are clearly issues.
Ah, do they back-seat-drive
each other's rectals?
What is that
a euphemism for?
Nothing. I literally just
experienced that with
Dr. Altman and Dr. Hunt.
Why is everyone married
to each other?
Because doctors
have no lives
and no time
to meet normal people.
♪ Are you ready? Mm-hmm
[ Cellphone chimes ]
Great.
Everything sucks.
♪ Gonna have a good time
♪ Tell me, are you ready?
Mm-hmm ♪
♪ Gonna have a good time
♪
Jules: Are you flirting with me
on a sick patient's leg?
Link: No. No, no, no.
No, no, no. No.
Crap. No.
That is not me flirting.
That is me being
an encouraging teacher.
Supportive.
In an appropriate way.
Uh, I didn't put a winky face
next to it or anything.
I-I genuinely don't want you
to cut off the wrong leg.
♪
♪ Tell me, are you ready?
Tell me, are you ready? ♪
Ten blade, please.
♪ Tell me, are you ready?
♪ Gonna have a good time
Tell me, are you ready? ♪
♪ Tell me, are you ready?
♪ Gonna have a good time,
good time ♪
♪ Mm-mm
♪ Mm-mm, mm-mm
[ Monitors beeping rapidly ]
[ Door opens ]
What happened?
He just started breathing
really hard,
then he made
this choking sound.
Is he dead?
He's in cardiac arrest.
He needs to be intubated.
Should I get Dr. Altman?
No, there's no time.
Mrs. Peters,
I need you to step outside.
But Harold--
We're gonna take care
of him, okay?
Wait, you're gonna do it?
Nope.
I'm gonna walk you
through it now.
Switch with me.
[ Breathing deeply ]
Okay, don't over-think this, Yasuda.
Make sure you have everything
ready that you need.
Test the tube.
Tube looks good. Stylet.
Okay, grab the scope.
Okay. Other way.
Ah, sorry.
Visualize the cords.
Okay.
Ready?
Okay. I can see them.
Take the tube. Insert it.
We don't have much time here,
so one fluid motion.
Trust your instincts
on the angle.
I got it through.
[ Breathing heavily ]
Cuffs up.
Let's start bagging.
Well?
Breath sounds
on both sides.
Breath sounds on both sides.
Nice work, Yasuda.
Airway is secured.
All we need to do now is, uh,
get his circulation back.
Good job.
I requested a single room.
Grew up an only child
and have-- or had--
social anxiety.
Dreaded meeting new people,
large parties.
Anytime I got an e-mail
during orientation
with the word "mixer" in
the subject line, I-I panicked.
Then Student Services
assigned me a roommate.
And I almost dropped out.
Till I met Chase.
I know this is gonna sound
really weird,
but you know those
emotional support animals
for people who can't handle
crowded places?
You're comparing him
to... a dog.
[ Chuckles ]
He fixed all my issues!
I mean, he-- he showed me how
to walk up to a group of people
and actually talk to them.
We haven't gotten into
a single fight,
and we basically live
on top of each other
inside of
a crowded dorm.
I mean, we've had colds
together, flu, athlete's foot,
which I don't know
if you've had, but--
Crowded dorm.
Do you know
if Chase received
all of his childhood
vaccinations?
I don't know. Why?
I-Is he gonna be okay?
I hope so!
I know this goes against
everything you've been taught,
but you need
to cut harder.
All the way through the joint,
layer by layer.
[ Door opens,
Simone breathing heavily ]
Link: Griffith?
Simone: The food poisoning
was a distractor.
Chase has meningococcus.
His cultures came back?
Not finalized,
but I checked his records.
He was never vaccinated for it,
and his gram stain is showing
gram-negative diplococci.
Meningococcus would explain
the septic shock.
Not to mention,
it's common in college--
College dorms.
Jules: There's too much blood.
I-I can't control the bleeding.
Oh, God. He's not clotting
properly due to the DIC.
Damn it.
I did everything you told me to!
Clamp.
Elevate the leg.
Turn up the tourniquet.
Clamp.
So residents now get
free weekly lunch...
Mm-hmm.
...attending mentors,
and an extra hour
of sleep?
Mm-hmm.
And let me guess,
there's a pinball machine
in the locker room now, too?
[ Laughs ] No.
Oh, but I did hear a rumor
about monthly passes
to a yoga studio.
[ Scoffs ]
You think the program's
gone soft.
No. I think it's finally headed
in the right direction.
I'm angry because
I tried
to implement similar changes
at various times
and was always met
with resistance.
You're allowed
to change your mind.
If you miss it,
you can come back.
I started a garden
at Pru's preschool.
We planted daffodils
and sunflowers
and talked about
plant life cycles
and how when you
plant a seed,
the roots have to grow first,
before anything else.
I wrote a sex education program
with a community clinic.
I'm answering phones
for a women's organization.
I am planting seeds.
Growing roots.
I-I think I'm following,
but--
I'm still not ready.
You're still not ready. No.
Okay.
♪
But, Wilson...
I do count you
as a mom friend.
[ Chuckles ]
♪
Altman paged me.
What do you got?
A central line.
I can't do it on my own.
Alright, okay.
You go ahead, Hunt.
Okay. Thank you.
I'm sure she loves
every moment of this.
You know,
she considers this payback
for the past six months
when I wasn't able to work.
I mean,
I was miserable, Richard.
I'm a trauma surgeon
who was trained in the military.
I am wired to work.
So instead of
sitting around drinking
and looking at people
with hate,
I surfed
to distract myself.
I built sand castles
to entertain my kids.
I wrote letters to Congress in
support of burn pit legislation.
And I maybe chose
the most expensive attorney
that I could find
to get my career back.
And you know what's hilarious?
She's the one who said
that we should run.
And I listened 'cause
she's my wife and I love her.
I love her
despite the fact
that she highlights
our credit-card bill balance
and posts it on the fridge
just so I don't forget
that we're broke.
So now, not only am I
living with someone
who resents me at home,
she stands over me
every second here at work.
Line's in.
Um...
I-I suggest you find
some physical space.
Yeah.
You got any ideas?
Man: [ Over intercom ]
Dr. Gear to the E.R., stat.
I'm sorry
I messed up your schedule.
Today,
or the past six months?
I know I've leaned on you,
and I-I'm sorry,
but you are so talented,
and I needed that in my O.R.
I needed to be able
to trust the person
standing next to me.
And we didn't have
any residents.
Now we do.
We have interns.
Okay. That makes it okay
to treat me
the way you used to treat me
back when we were at Tufts?
As your resident?
Of course not.
[ Sighs ] Why do you think
I'm so talented, Maggie?
Because you-- you are.
[ Chuckles ]
I mean, you've studied.
You've practiced.
You work really hard.
I had a good teacher.
That's why.
And you can't expect everyone
to be as good as you and me
unless you teach them.
Unless we teach them.
And I can't do that
if you're constantly
pulling me off my cases.
It's not fair to me.
It's not fair to my patients.
It's not fair
to this next class.
Okay.
Okay?
[ Sighs ] I really am
a good teacher, aren't I?
[ Laughs ]
Just don't let them
fall in love with you.
Because--
[ Both laugh ]
[ "Myself" by Marvin Brooks
playing ]
♪
He looks awful.
* Stony roads uphill
Meredith: But he's alive.
And he doesn't have a leg?
From the knee down.
But you can live without a leg.
And he has that option now.
Due to Dr. Griffith's
quick thinking.
The culture came back
for meningococcus.
His mom should be here soon,
but you can go and sit with him
so long as we get you
gowned and gloved.
Thank you. Okay.
♪ Can anybody hear me?
♪ Mama always said that
We'll all need to be on
a four-day regimen
of prophylactic antibiotics
due to the exposure.
♪ 'Cause you might just
burn yourself ♪
How's Millin?
I don't know.
Okay, well, Chase had
uncontrollable coagulopathy.
Any one of you would
have struggled to
control that bleeding.
So be there for her,
because when it's you
that makes the mistake--
I won't.
You wil and when you do,
those people are the only people
who will understand.
It's too early to go numb, Griffith.
What if I'm not
the comforting type?
Surely there must be something
that makes you feel better
when you have
a day like that.
♪ If this has a meanin',
then I will keep breathin' ♪
I have faith in you.
♪ As long as it takes
♪ Where will I go now,
I don't need to know now ♪
♪ No weight on my shoulder,
the wind will tell ♪
Mmm.
It's the only place in
the hospital that smells good.
Like peppermint.
♪ 'Cause you might
just burn yourself *
It's eucalyptus.
Stuffed animals
are pretty soft, too.
♪ Oh, I
♪ The more you inspire
♪ The more you see yourself
♪ Oh, ah
[ Knock on door ]
Meredith: Come in.
You paged?
Yeah. I just, uh--
I wanted to go over
this budget request
for the, um,
"Lunch & Learns."
What is a Lunch & Learn?
Well, the department
provides the interns protected
time for lunch once a week,
and rotating attendings
will lecture.
You really want
to talk about this right now?
Do you have
somewhere else to be?
Why does it seem like
you're mad at me?
I'm not.
You haven't said two words to me
since you've been here.
I thought,
since you were here--
That's just it.
Wha-- You thought what?
I-I kind of need you
to say it here, Meredith.
You need me to say what?
Great, you're both here.
We're in the middle
of something right now.
I can't work for Teddy.
It's been a day.
It's been a week.
But anyway, I talked an intern
through an intubation today,
and I was
pretty damn good at it,
so let me be a teacher
for these next six months.
That's how
I can be helpful.
I won't keep attendings away
from their own services,
and Schmitt won't be
run into the ground.
Let me work for you.
I'll teach labs,
skills, sutures, anything.
I'm your guy to teach.
Because I cannot
stand in that E.R.
with my wife
looking over my shoulder,
or only something terrible
will happen.
So save my marriage, Nick Marsh.
Please, save me.
Okay?
Oh. Sure.
Okay. Thank you.
Thank you for your time.
Thank you. Yeah.
If you disagree with
any of the changes, let me know.
Nick. Nick!
Look, I don't have time for all
this back and forth, Meredith.
And based on the way
people just walk on in here,
neither do you.
Good night.
I went numb.
The program shut down,
and we lost a patient.
And you didn't have my back.
You know how many people
I've lost in my life.
And when I watched you
walk away,
and I thought I lost you,
then I went numb.
That's why I didn't call you
for six months.
An then when I saw you
in the surgical corridor, I...
[ Sighs ]
I could feel again.
I know I'm still
in love with you.
[ Sighs ]
I know my life is crazy.
And I know
I can't stop people
from coming in the door
every five minutes
and interrupting
absolutely everything I do.
♪
But I do know
that I love you.
So if that's
what you need to hear,
I'll say it, as many times
as you need to hear it.
♪
Can I take you to dinner?
Let me take you
to dinner.
No.
No?
But you can take me
to Zola's presentation
for the Pacific
Northwest Scholars.
I'm in.
Okay.
See you tonight.
Meredith: Tension exists
throughout the entire body.
♪ Ooh
How it affects you
depends on how you manage it.
Why?
It's a coping mechanism.
There was a study
out of Amsterdam
that said when people touch
stuffed animals,
especially if they have
low self-esteem,
it helps relieve anxiety.
I don't have
low self-esteem.
I intubated
a patient today.
Neither does Adams.
He's sleeping with Dr. Shepherd,
chief of neuro.
What? I--
Well, it makes me feel better.
I'm not. Why-- Why-- Why
would you think that?
Uh, I saw you two coming out
of the on-call room together,
whispering in the halls.
Unless you have
a different explanation?
♪
- [ Sighs ]
- Geez.
Oh, everyone owes me $12
for the stuffed animals.
Nope.
Who gives people a present
then asks them to pay for it?
Hey.
♪ I will walk
I'm more of a cat person.
Some people can self-regulate
by breathing,
meditation, exercise.
They develop tools
that help them fight the stress
and reduce the pain it causes.
Zola: While at
the Clinic in Minnesota,
Dr. Grey conducted
six different clinical trials
that helped lead to advances
in cellular regeneration
related to liver disease.
She began a seventh, but she
unfortunately never completed it
because she started
exhibiting signs
of early onset
Alzheimer's disease.
Early--
[ Breathes shakily ]
Early onset Alzheimer's
disease can be a...
[ Feedback ]
But not all people
are wired that way.
Be a...
♪ Where's the saving grace?
Early onset Alzheimer's can be
a genetic illness in which...
Zola: [ Muffled ]
Alzheimer's can be a...
Um, it's genetic,
which means...
Meredith: Some people feel
completely overwhelmed by it.
Something's wrong.
It's genetic. It means...
[ Voice breaking ]
It means my mom and my aunt,
they'll get it, too.
They'll get it. They're gonna
die, and I'll have no one.
My aunt and my mom
are gonna die.
They're gonna die.
And the tension
freezes their bodies
until they can't move at all.
It's okay.
[ Zola breathing shakily ]
♪
- Captions by VITAC--